downloadzone.org 2013-08-22

# Privacy Policy - Download Zone

LAST UPDATED: 2013-05-21

downloadzone.org, and its Subsidiaries are committed to safeguarding your privacy online. This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") discloses how we collect and use information, and the choices that you can make about the way we collect and use your information.

If you are under 18, you should ask your parents or a guardian before you use our Services. If you are not yet 18, do not use our Services; do not download our products.

This Privacy Policy applies to any customers who use our Services. Collection, use, disclosure, and protection of personal information may be subject to different regulations outside the United States. Regardless, if you use our Sites, Products or Services you agree to abide by this policy.

Sites Covered by This Policy: downloadzone.org and other sites we own that post a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively "Sites"). This Privacy Policy also applies to our desktop software (collectively "Products"). This Privacy Policy may also apply to new Sites and Products we develop.

### Overview of Our Policy

We supply free entertainment software including but not limited to screensavers, download managers, and wallpapers for your Desktop on our Sites. (We refer to our software and Products throughout this agreement as our “Services”).

We offer our Services to you in exchange for your agreement to receive e-mail, view promotions, advertisements, or participate in other offers. We also offer you the opportunity to download third-party software.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully so that you understand our online privacy practices regarding: Information We Collect, How We Use Your Information, How We Use and Share Your Information, Your Choices

We may make available shorter versions of this Privacy Policy. We also may supplement this policy for specific Services. Where there is a conflict between this policy and our summary this policy will govern. Where there is a conflict between this policy and our supplement, the supplement will govern.

We may change this privacy policy. If we change this policy we will post the changes to this privacy statement, our websites’ homepages, and other places we deem appropriate. We reserve the right to modify this policy at any time. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

### Some Terms We Use in This Policy

Offers include e-mail, promotions, advertisements contests and third-party software presented by our Partners and us.

Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is any information that identifies or could be used to identify, contact or locate you. It also includes your credit card number.

Partner is an advertiser, or other entity with whom we have a business relationship to provide Offers.

Service includes, but is not limited to, our screensaver, wallpaper, game, animated gif, clip art, buddy icon, greeting card, browser skin, font, desktop theme, html editor, sound effect, social networking, download manager, storage, and calendar software.

Subsidiary is an entity wholly owned or related to downloadzone.org.

User means an individual that has accessed the Sites on which we host our Products or Services.

We and Our refer to downloadzone.org and its subsidiaries.

You and Your refer to each user and his or her agents.

### Personal Information We Collect

We may collect personal information at various times when you use our Services. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Your participation is voluntary and you have the choice not to disclose any information that we request.

### Download/Installation.

During download or installation, we will present you with Offers. You may choose not to accept our Offers. Your participation is voluntary, you are not required to disclose to our Partners any information they request. However, if you provide your Personally Identifiable Information in response to any Offer, we will share it with our Partners so they can provide you with the Offers in which you have expressed interest.

### Contacts/IP Information.

If you voluntarily submit information or contact us (e.g. password request, technical support), we may keep a record of this communication. We do not merge this information with your Personally Identifiable Information.

### Contact Us.

We collect your name and email address on the Sites’ “Contact us” forms. We use this information for the sole purpose of responding to your inquiry.

### Customer Support.

If you use the customer support section on the Sites we will collect your email address, topic and any addition information you provide us. We use this information for the sole purpose of responding to your inquiry.

### Free Games.

We offer free games. Some of our games collect your name as a requisite to setting up a profile. We use this information for the sole purpose of setting up your profile.

### Aggregate Information We Collect

When you use our Services, we may collect tracking information such as your IP address, browser type, the type of operating system you use, details about your computer hardware, the applications you have installed on your PC, the domain name of your Internet service provider, and pages you visited on our Sites. None of the information identifies you personally and we do not link aggregate information to Personally Identifiable Information.

### Cookies.

A cookie is a small text file sent to your browser. Cookies are stored on your computer's hard drive for record keeping purposes. We and our Partners may use session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once you close your browser, the cookie will terminate. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s help file.

We may use cookies to: 1) Remind us of who you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers). We also use cookies to store your zip code and other information you have submitted for other services, such as displaying your local weather; 2) Record your Blog URL and Username on your local computer to allow us to remember you on your next visit; 3) Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing our Services is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by registered users and unregistered users, and to help target advertisements based on user interests; 4) Allows our Partners to track visits to their sites and stores. This information collected by cookies is sometimes called "clickstream" or "click trail" and may also describe which pages you have seen; 5) Measure certain traffic patterns, for example which of our Sites you have visited. We use this information to understand our users' habits so that we can make each new experience on a Site a better one. We may also use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you will see. We do not store Personally Identifiable Information in our cookies and we do not tie the information in our cookies to our customers’ Personally Identifiable Information

Some of the Partner Offers on our Services may also use affiliate cookies after you click on their offer in order to track the offer. We have no control over our partners’ privacy policies. We also have no control over their cookies, the information collected and its use.

### Web beacons or Pixels.

We and our Partners employ a software technology that helps us better manage content on our site. Web beacons or Pixels are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. They track your online Web movement. We embed Pixels invisibly on Web pages. They are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by Pixels to our customers’ Personally Identifiable Information.

Some of the Partner Offers may also use Pixels. We have no control over our partners’ Pixels. We also have no control over how they use information collected.

We may use third-party web beacons to help analyze where visitors go and what they do while visiting our website. The third parties may also use anonymous information about your visits to this and other websites in order to improve its products and services and provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 

### Global Unique Identifiers.

A GUID (global unique identifier) is a randomly generated alphanumeric identifier used to indicate a unique installation of our Products or Services. We may create a GUID when you install our Products or Services. We use GUIDs to track installations and to enable features and functionality for specific customers who subscribe to our Products and Services. We do not tie the information gathered by GUIDs to our customers’ Personally Identifiable Information.

### Software Information.

We employ a technology that allows us to determine the operating systems you are using and to view your computer’s registry. Software installed on your computer has unique registry keys. By viewing your registry, we are able to detect whether you have a compatible operating system, compatible versions of DirectX, and Flash Player installed. We use your registry information to determine whether our software offers are compatible with software already present on your PC. We do not tie registry information gathered to our customers’ Personally Identifiable Information.

### Hardware Information.

Your computer’s operating system also stores hardware information that we examine to determine your computer’s hardware configuration including the amount of memory and the type of video card your computer has, as well as the speed of your processor. We use the information to determine whether our software offers are compatible with your computer hardware. We do not tie hardware information to our customers’ Personally Identifiable Information.

### MAC Address.

Your computer's MAC address is a unique code, an alphanumeric identifier, assigned to your computer. We may collect your computer's MAC address when you install our Products or Services. We use your computer's MAC address to track unique installations of our Products and Services. We do not combine your computer's MAC address with any other information about you.

### How We Use Your Information

Our primary goal is to make our Services more useful to you. By knowing about you, we are able to deliver relevant Services and Offers. We maintain a secure database of all Personally Identifiable Information collected on our Sites and Services.

### E-mail Offers.

By providing your e-mail address, and choosing to receive our Offers, you agree to receive e-mails from us. Should you have any questions or concerns, or if you would like to discontinue receiving Offers, simply email us at privacy@downloadzone.org and ask us to remove you from our lists. You will only receive Offers via e-mail from us and our Partners if you have indicated that you would like to receive them.

### Testimonials.

We post testimonials on our Sites. Testimonials may contain Personally Identifiable Information. We will obtain your consent via email prior to posting the testimonial or comment.

### Research.

We study users' demographics and interests using your information. We also use cookies, pixels, software checker information and server log files to better understand and serve you. We compile and analyze this information on an aggregated basis. We also may share this aggregated data periodically with current and potential Partners.

### Third Parties and Advertising.

Third parties advertise on our Sites, and we also contract with third parties to serve ads across the Internet. These third parties may serve ads about our products or services, or third party products or services in which, based on your Session Data, we or our business partners believe you may be interested. These third parties may seek to use cookies and pixel tags, including those collected on our Site, to track Session Data about the ads you have seen and types of things in which you appear interested. These third parties may also use combined information about your visits to our Site and other sites in order to provide advertisements about related goods and services that may be of interest to you. You can opt-out of the third party advertising program by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative website http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp. Opting out of a network does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising. It does mean that the network from which you opted out will no longer deliver ads tailored to your Web preferences and usage patterns.

When you click on a third party advertisers' link from our Site, you will enter the third party's site. We are not responsible for such third party's sites. You should carefully review the privacy statements of any other site you visit, because those privacy statements will apply to your visit to that site, and may be very different from our policy.

### Surveys.

From time-to-time we conduct surveys. If you participate we may request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participating in surveys is completely voluntary. We use survey information to improve our Sites. We use any personally identifiable information for the sole purpose of contacting you to follow-up on your survey responses. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provided in a survey with any third-party unless we have your consent. On occasion we may hire a third-party to conduct a survey. If we hire a third-party service provider it will be prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any purpose not enumerated in this section.

### How We Share Your Information.

Partners may sponsor Offers or we may co-sponsor an Offer with a Partner through the software. You should always assume data collected when you fill-in an Offer will be shared with a Partner. If an Offer requires you to leave our websites, you should know that our Partners may collect Personally Identifiable Information about you. We do not control these Partner sites. This Privacy Policy does not cover our partners’ websites and information practices. Once you have voluntarily submitted information to our Partners, your personal information is subject to their privacy policy. We have no liability or responsibility for these privacy policies or the use of any Personally Identifiable Information transferred to Partners.

If you no longer wish to be contacted by our partners you must contact that partner directly to opt-out.

Our Partners change from time to time, and therefore it is not possible to provide an exhaustive list. We strive to select trustworthy Partners who offer high quality products or services of interest to you. If you are unhappy with one of our Partners, tell us by e-mailing us at partneralert@downloadzone.org.

We may periodically use third parties to meet your needs. For example we might use a credit card processing company to bill you. If we will use a third-party we will notify you at sign-up. If we hire a third-party service provider, they will be prohibited from using your Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose not enumerated in this section.

The following describes some of the ways that we may disclose your information to our Partners:

### Search Partners.

We may transmit your search queries (made on the Site or within one of our Software Offers) to search Partners, who use this information to provide us with search results, which we then will display to you.

### Third-Party Advertisements and Software.

When you request or submit your information online to a Partner in response to any Offer, we transfer your information for each request made to that Partner. Once we transfer your Personally Identifiable Information, such information becomes subject to the Partners’ privacy policy.

### Our Products.

We do not require you to provide Personally Identifiable Information during the download or installation process. However, when you use these Software Offers to access Download Offers (e.g. screensavers) you may be required to provide Personally Identifiable Information. In addition, we will show you Offers during the download or installation process.

### Other Limited Circumstances.

From time to time, we may validate the information in our database by employing a validation service. In those instances, we will disclose your information pursuant to confidentiality agreements. In addition, we disclose aggregated user statistics (for example, 45% of our users are female) when we market to current and prospective Partners and for other lawful purposes.

### Legal Disclosure.

We may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our policies or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights, property, users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. We may disclose account information, as required by law, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or to comply with a judicial procedure served on our sites; or if the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain service and improve our Products and Services.

### E-Mail Suppression Lists.

We may disclose a user’s e-mail address as part of a suppression file or do-not-e-mail list to its partners and affiliates to make sure that a user’s unsubscribe requests are forwarded to the appropriate parties to ensure removal of the user from partner and affiliate databases in compliance with law, including without limitation, the Can-Spam Act of 2003.

### Sale, Merger or Asset Transfer.

We may buy other businesses or their assets or sell our business assets. Customer information is generally one of the business assets involved in such transactions. Thus, in the event that we or all of our assets are acquired, customer information, including any information collected through the Sites or the Services would be one of the transferred assets.

From time to time we use third-parties when providing Services to you. We will only share information with third-parties necessary for them to provide the Services you have requested. Third-parties are prohibited from using your Personally Identifiable Information for promotional purposes.

#### Your Choices

### Cookies.

By modifying your browser preferences, you can choose to, accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or you can reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies, you may be unable to use our Services.

### Offers.

We may from time to time, send you e-mail regarding third party promotions, as well as other, Products and Services. In addition, if you indicated upon registration that you are interested in receiving offers or information from us and our Partners, we may occasionally send you e-mail or direct postal mail about other products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive e-mail or postal mail from us, you can tell us by e-mailing us at privacy@downloadzone.org. Be sure to include your full name and address, along with the information you submitted during your initial registration including postal address and e-mail, and tell us that you no longer wish to receive Offers from us. You also have the option of unsubscribing from e-mail Offers by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of every e-mail offer from us.

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you want your information deleted from our systems you should email our customer support team as support@downloadzone.org.

### Additional Information.

At any time you may send us an e-mail to privacy@downloadzone.org to request a listing of all personal information disclosed by us to third parties or Partners. If requested, we will provide an e-mail response within thirty (30) days informing you of the recipients of your Personally Identifiable Information and the information disclosed to third parties.

### Security and Passwords

We cannot and do not ensure or warrant the security of any information collected, transmitted over the Internet, or maintained in your user profile. You agree that any data transmission you make or receive through the Site or the Service is at your own risk.

No method of transmitting or storing electronic data is ever completely secure, and therefore we cannot warrant or guarantee that such information will never be accessed, used, or released in a manner that is inconsistent with this policy.

We do not knowingly collect information about children under the age of 13. We encourage parents and guardians to be familiar with the web sites that their children visit. The Federal Trade Commission ("FTC") regulates the means by which web site operators collect and use personal information from children under 13, pursuant to the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (the "Act"). For more information about the Act and children's on-line privacy in general, visit the FTC's web site at www.ftc.gov/privacy. For safety tips on privacy visit www.OnGuardOnline.gov.

### Miscellaneous Provisions

YOUR USE OF OUR SERVICES IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. OUR SERVICES (INCLUDING ALL CONTENT AND FUNCTIONS MADE AVAILABLE ON OR ACCESSED THROUGH OUR SITES) IS PROVIDED "AS IS." WE MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND WHATSOEVER ABOUT: (1) THE ACCURACY, MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT; (2) THE SERVER THAT MAKES THE SERVICES AVAILABLE, INCLUDING THAT IT IS FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER COMPONENTS THAT MAY INFECT, HARM, OR CAUSE DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER EQUIPMENT OR ANY OTHER PROPERTY WHEN YOU ACCESS, BROWSE, DOWNLOAD FROM, OR OTHERWISE USE THE SITE.

UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO OUR NEGLIGENCE, SHALL WE BE LIABLE FOR ANY CONSEQUENTIAL, DIRECT, INCIDENTAL, INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, OR SPECIAL DAMAGES RELATED TO (A) THE USE OF, (B) THE INABILITY TO USE, OR (C) ERRORS OR OMISSIONS IN THE CONTENTS AND FUNCTIONS OF OUR SITES AND SERVICES, EVEN IF WE OR OUR REPRESENTATIVES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. SOME STATES DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, SO THE ABOVE LIMITATION OR EXCLUSION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU. IN NO EVENT SHALL OUR TOTAL LIABILITY TO YOU FOR ALL DAMAGES, LOSSES, AND CAUSES OF ACTION (WHETHER IN CONTRACT OR TORT, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) EXCEED $10.00.

### Indemnification.

You agree to indemnify, defend, and hold us and all of our agents, directors, employees, information providers, licensors and licensees, officers, and subsidiaries (collectively, "Indemnified Parties") harmless from and against any and all liability and costs (including, without limitation, attorneys' fees and costs) incurred by you in connection with any claim arising out of any breach by you of this Privacy Policy. You will cooperate as fully as reasonably required in our defense of any claim. We reserve the right, at our own expense, to assume the exclusive defense and control of any matter otherwise subject to indemnification by you and you shall not in any event settle any matter without our written consent.

### International Policy.

Our Services are hosted by servers in the United States. Accordingly, if you are located outside of the United States, we will transfer the personal information you provide to us in the United States. By submitting your personal information, you fully understand and consent, to its transfer, storage and processing in the United States.

### Enforcement / Redress.

If you feel that we have not followed our Privacy policy, please let us know. Also, if you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy policy, its implementation, or would like a written copy, please feel free to contact us at:

downloadzone.org

contact us via e-mail at privacy@downloadzone.org
